"行尸走肉"前情提要...
Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
如果栅栏再这样被压着 行尸就要爬过来了
The fence keeps bending in like that, those walkers are coming over it.
那所兽医大学里...
That veterinary college...
宠物用的药我们一样可以用
The drugs are the same we need.
包 导管 钳子 连接器
Bags, tubes, claps, connectors.
清单上所有的东西都拿到了
Everything on the list.
好的 我们走
All right, let's roll.
我不能让你这么胡闹
I can't let you do this.
那些人们在经受着痛苦
There are people in there suffering.
是你杀了Karen和David吗?
Did you kill Karen and David?
是的
Yes.
我会把你赶走的
I won't have you there.
但你会在外面活下来
You're gonna survive out here.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 波特妹子 时间轴: 有个饭团
翻译: 初见 酱油影 Evayao
校对: 潇妹子
Henry 别激动
Henry, I need you to calm down.
我们在帮你
We're trying to help.
不...!
No...!
你们两个快喝点茶水
Drink some of that. Both of you.
是不是得开个会?
Some council meeting, huh?
还有两个成员没回来
We're two members short.
在他们回来之前 我们应该定些新规矩
I think we should make some new rules before they get back.
比如说 以后意大利面之夜
I hereby declare we have spaghetti Tuesdays
从周二改到周三
every Wednesday.
我们的意大利面不够吃了
First we have to find some spaghetti.
你可以负责照顾他吗?
You okay to take over?
每隔五到六秒捏一下
Every five to six seconds, squeeze.
如果你觉得头晕了
You start feeling lightheaded,
就让别人来接替你
grab somebody else to take over.
我们轮流来照顾他
We'll take it in shifts.
想不想跟我一块去巡查?
You want to help me go on my rounds?
嗯
Yeah.
好的
Sure.
这样能让他活多久?
How long will that keep him alive?
只要我们一直这样照顾他
Just as long as we're willing to do it.
他就可以活着
As long as it takes.
不 别在这里这么做
No. Not here.
帮我把他抬到这上面
Help me get him on this.
好吧 但是几小时后Henry死了...
Okay, but in a couple of hours when Henry's dead...
- Glenn  - 你打算怎么把他的尸体
- Glenn.  - How are we gonna get his body
经过牢房搬下楼梯
down the stairs, across the cell block
还不让别人看到?
and through those doors without anyone noticing?
真死了... 假设死了... 你就得给我帮忙
If that happens... if... you're gonna help me.
如果我也死了呢?
And what if I'm gone?
别废话 赶紧把他抬上来
Shut up and help me get him on this.
你们在干嘛?
What are you doing?
我们把Jacobson先生搬到安静点的地方休养
We're taking Mr. Jacobson to a quieter place.
去我的房间把那本"汤姆・索亚历险记"拿来
Go get my copy of "Tom Sawyer" from my room.
你今晚可以读读它
I want you to read it by tonight.
我们都有事要做
We all got jobs to do.
- 你的事就是读书  - 我读不完
- That one's yours.  - I won't finish it.
怎么了?
Why?
晚上太黑了
It's gonna get too dark.
哦
Well,
尽力读吧
give it your best try.
多喝点茶水
And drink some tea.
你没责任这么做 对吧?
You haven't had to do this yet, have you?
昨晚后半夜就有一个
There was one late last night.
Sasha这么做了
Sasha did it.
人们不应该看到这一幕
People don't need to see it.
我不希望他们看到
I don't want them to.
行尸走肉 第四季第五集
Glenn哪去了? 他说过会回来见我
Where's Glenn? He said he would meet me.
他在休息
He's resting.
他没事吧?
Is he okay?
他刚在帮我的忙
He was helping me
现在有点累了 就是这样
and he got tired, that's all.
- 要帮忙可以找我  - 不用了
- If you need help, I can help you. - I don't.
我只是想让他有事情做
I was just keeping him occupied.
让他一直想着帮别人
Keeping his mind on helping people.
我可以进去帮你
I can come in there and help you.
不用你来
No, you don't need to.
- 你该休息一下 爸...  - 不!
- You can rest, dad...  - No!
Bethy怎么样了?
How's Bethy?
她没事
She's okay.
爸 你看起来很疲惫
Daddy, you look so tired.
确实有点累
I am.
但我没事
But I'm fine.
他们随时可能回来
They could return any minute now.
这里处境艰难
It's hard in here.
但我们团结一心
But we're holding it together.
就会度过难关
We're gonna make it.
你不相信吗?
Don't you believe that?
当然相信
Of course.
再多坚持一段时间
Just hold it together a little longer.
行吗?
Please?
我爱你 宝贝
I love you, honey.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
谢谢你没让她进来
Thank you for stopping her.
外面也需要有人照顾
We need someone out there taking care of things.
如果她看到我这样
If she saw me,
肯定会进来
couldn't keep her out.
我知道你不是故意骗她
I know you didn't want to lie to her.
我没骗她
I wasn't lying.
你确实在休息
Look at you. You're resting.
都差不多弄好了
I'm almost done down here.
你去躺一会吧
Why don't you go lie down?
Carl和Judith还好吗?
Carl, Judith, are they okay?
嗯 Carol呢?
Yeah. Where's Carol?
Glenn Hershel和Sasha呢?
Glenn, Hershel, Sasha?
嗯 情况很糟 但他们正在和疾病斗争 Daryl还没回来
Yeah, it's bad, but they're fighting it. Daryl's not back yet.
Rick Carol哪去了?
Rick. Rick, where's Carol?
凶手是她
It was her.
是她杀了Karen和David
She killed Karen and David.
她只是想停止瘟疫扩散
She was trying to stop it from spreading.
Tyreese马上就要回来了
Tyreese is gonna be back here soon,
我觉得她不能待在这儿
so I didn't think she should be here.
我也不能让她留在这儿
And I couldn't have her here.
她有车和补给
She has a car, supplies,
她会有办法活下去的
she'll figure it out.
我去告诉你爸爸 先别告诉其他人
I'll tell your dad. Don't tell anyone else yet.
好的
Okay.
换作是你 你会把她带回来吗?
Would you have brought her back?
- 她亲口承认了吗?  - 是的
- She said she did it?  - Yeah.
那你的确应该把她驱逐出去
Then you were right to send her away.
我不知道我是否也能做到
I don't know if I could have.
你也会这么做的 Maggie
You could have, Maggie.
你做过更艰难的决定
You've done harder things.
别怀疑你自己 我们可不能再这样
Don't doubt yourself. We don't get to anymore.
Rick 行尸的数量比上次压倒铁栅栏的更多了
Rick, the cluster's getting bigger than the one that took the fence down.
- 我们得想想办法  - 会有办法的
- We need to do something.  - We will.
Carl 在吗?
Carl?
嘿 Carl
Carl.
Carl 听到吗?
Carl?
你没事吧?
You okay?
我也想问你呢
I was gonna ask you that.
- 我们没事  - 没人生病吧?
- We're fine.  - No one's sick?
你不需要动手吧?
You didn't have to do anything?
还没用过我的枪 爸爸
Haven't had to use my gun, Dad.
Judith呢?
And Judith?
她和Beth在一起
She's with Beth.
很好
Good.
我出去的时候找到了些食物
Found some food on the run.
里面有不少干无花果
There's a bunch of fruit leather in there.
让大家吃完都刷刷牙
Have everybody brush their teeth after.
- 我们很快就能出去吗?  - 还不行
- Can we come out soon?  - Not just yet.
爸爸 你当时冲锋陷阵的时候我就在你身边
Dad, I was around you when you were in the middle of it.
我也和Patrick接触过
And I was around Patrick.
但我没得病 我能帮助你
I didn't get it. I can help you.
谢谢 不过我还是要你待在这儿
Thanks, but I need you to stay here.
我会的
I will.
但爸爸 你没法保护我一辈子不干那事儿
But, Dad, you can't keep me from it.
什么事?
From what?
就是要动手杀人的事
From what always happens.
没错
Yeah.
也许吧
Maybe.
但努力保护你就是我的工作
But I think it's my job to try.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
No problem.
让我来看看你的病情
Let's have a look at you.
医生往往是最差劲的病人
Doctors make the worst patients.
并不是所有人都得活下去
Not everyone gets to live.
末期
End stage
就是没人能从中恢复的阶段
is a point that no one comes back from
或者... 他们就活不了了
or they... or they can't.
我就是末期了
That's where I am.
不 你得集中精神帮助那些病情较轻的人
No, you need to focus on the ones that can make it.
我又做了些静脉注射液
I made some more IVs.
如果你没做好失去一个人的准备
If you're not ready to lose one,
那可能导致更多人死去
you're gonna lose them all.
就像是关灯...
It's like turning off a light...
总会一盏接着一盏熄灭
it'll happen one after the other.
他们不仅仅是死了
And they don't just die.
我们能坚持
We can hold on.
嘿 Caleb
Caleb.
别动
自从另外那个区域出事之后
After what happened in the other cell block,
我来这里的时候就带了这个
when I came in here, I brought these.
快坐回床上去 事情还没那么糟
Get back in bed now. We're not that bad off.
等局面急转直下
When we are,
一切就都晚了
it'll be too late.
你不明白
You don't understand.
你有机会
You have a chance.
情况马上就会恶化的
This is it after this.
我不会放弃任何一个人
I'm not giving up on anyone.
至少现在不会
Not yet.
你得保证大家的房门都关上
Just make sure everyone's doors are shut.
Caleb 别...
Caleb...
你得保证!
Just make sure!
Caleb 让我看看你的病情
Caleb, you've got to let me look at you.
好吧 Hershel
Okay, Hershel.
你就看吧
Have a look.
喝点我留给你的茶
Drink the tea I left you.
我一个小时后再回来看你
Gonna be back to check on you in an hour.
各位
Everyone,
回各自的房间去
get back in your cells.
快点回各自的房间去
Go on, get back in your cells.
把他搬到这床上
Let's get him on this.
去休息吧
Go rest.
你能自己走回房间吗?
Can you make it to your cell?
# 你走吧 #
# Go your way #
# 我要绕远路 #
# I'll take the long way around #
# 我会找到下去的路 #
# I'll find my own way down #
# 如同我该做的那样 #
# As I should #
# 遥望远方 #
# And hold your gaze #
# 点石成金之道也有弊端 #
# There's coke in the Midas touch #
# 玩笑中 我们老去 #
# A joke in the way that we rust #
# 再呼吸一次... #
# And breathe again... #
嘿 Hershel
Hershel.
这是死的第三个了
Third one we've lost.
我们在楼后面烧了他们
We're burning them behind the blocks.
烧了他们
Burning them.
只有这一种方法了
That's what it's come to.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
我昨天刚跟他聊过斯坦贝克的小说
I talked to him yesterday about Steinbeck.
他引用了一句话
He told me a quote.
"悲伤的灵魂
"A sad soul
比细菌更致命"
can kill quicker than a germ."
这也正是我不想给所有人看到这一幕的原因
That's exactly why I didn't want them all to see what happens.
我知道他们都明白
I know they know,
但就是不想让他们现在就看到
but I didn't want them to see it right now.
他们都看着你 Hershel
They're seeing you, Hershel.
他们看着你
They see you
不言放弃
keep going.
哪怕是已经快无计可施的时候
Even after all the choices keep getting taken away.
等我们撑过这一关...
When we get past this thing...
也不会和以前一样了 对吧?
it's not gonna be like how it was, is it?
对
No.
你是在否认吗?
Was that denial?
你觉得我没有透过表象看本质?
Not seeing things for how they were?
对
No.
你正好找到了突破口
You just caught a break.
你需要时间 也得到了时间
You needed some time. You got some.
你运气好
You got lucky.
我们都是
We all did.
我仍然觉得会有办法
I still think there's a plan.
我也相信这一切肯定有缘由
I still believe there's a reason.
你觉得这是试炼?
You think it's all a test?
生活本身就是试炼 Rick
Life was always a test, Rick.
我得跟你谈谈Carol的事情
I need to talk to you about Carol.
醒醒
Come on.
醒醒 Sasha
Come on, Sasha.
你知道怎么抗争
You know how to fight.
坚持住
Just hold on.
坚持住 千万别放弃
Just hold on. Don't give up on me, now.
我刚和你爸爸谈过
I just talked to your dad.
他看上去不错 也自有考量
He looks good, all things considered.
如果Carl病了 你会上去陪他吗?
If Carl were sick, would you be up there with him?
如果我能帮上忙的话就会
If I thought I could help.
你觉得我帮不上忙?
You don't think I can help?
该死
Damn.
真高兴你跟我一起在这儿
I'm just glad you're out here with me.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我晕过去了?
I passed out?
你脱水了
You were dehydrated.
充当英雄消耗了你很多体力
Being a hero takes a lot out of you.
你应该知道的
You should know.
我觉得你真是蠢透了才会进来
I thought you were an idiot to come in here.
我本来以为你会变成一个
I mean, I was sure you were just gonna be
死掉的老蠢蛋
a dead foolish man.
我分不清楚这是不是在表扬我
I can't tell if that's a compliment.
我不知道我在说什么
I don't know what I'm saying.
肯定是撞到头了
I must have hit my head.
我不相信魔法
I don't believe in magic
或是运气
or luck.
我会小心计算
I do the math
不会冒险赌博
and I don't gamble.
但我觉得如果你没做蠢事
But I don't know if I'd be here right now
我就活不到现在
if you weren't so damn stupid.
知道吗?
You know what?
我就当你是在表扬我了
I'm gonna take that as a compliment.
嘿 Hersh...
Hersh...
嘿 Hershel...
Hershel...
我一会儿再来看你
I'll check on you in a little while.
他怎么样?
How is he?
睡着了
He's sleeping.
你也应该休息一会儿
You should get some rest yourself.
我不想离开他 以防他醒过来
I don't want to leave him in case he wakes up.
- 想让我看看他吗?  - 不用
- Want me to take a look at him?  - No.
让他睡吧
Just let him sleep.
嘿 Hershel!
Hershel!
大家都待在房间里
Everyone stay in your cells.
不
No.
去吧
Go.
铁栅栏更重要 我们不能让它倒掉
The fence is more important. We need to keep it standing.
我来处理
I got this.
- 你一个人干不了  - 我知道 你去吧
- You can't do this alone.  - I know. Go.
跟着我 Henry
Just follow me, Henry.
快来这儿 离开Glenn 快点
Down here, away from Glenn. Come on.
快点 Henry 这边走
Come on, Henry. Here we go. This way.
快点 跟着我 Henry
Come on, boy. Come on, Henry.
再往这儿走点
Just a little more.
接着走
Keep coming.
乖孩子 跟我走 快点
Come on, boy. Let's go. Come on.
Carl 听到吗?
Carl?
Carl...?
嘿 Carl
Carl.
我听到了枪声
I heard gunshots.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
快点 来这儿 Henry
Come on. Down here, Henry.
跟着我 过来
Keep following me. Come here.
再过来点
A little further.
Henry 过来...
Henry, come on...
- 你没事吧?  - 我小声叫他的
- You okay?  - I called him nice.
他没抓伤Glenn 我觉得他能听懂我说话
He didn't scratch Glenn. I thought maybe he listens.
- Glenn在哪儿 Lizzy?  - 他的房间
- Lizzy, where is Glenn?  - His cell.
爸爸!
Dad!
爸爸! 开门!
Dad! Open the door!
快回里面去
Get back in there.
你俩待在这别动
You two stay put in here.
坚持住 Glenn 坚持
Hold on, Glenn. Hold on.
Hershel啊!
Hershel!
Caleb  Caleb 我们需要枪
Caleb. Caleb, we need the gun.
他们应该没事吗?
Think they're okay?
如果有事 我们会听到更多枪声
If things were going bad, we would have heard more shots.
Maggie也会来找我们
Maggie would have gotten us.
我们得加固篱笆
We have to do this.
那做吧
Let's do it.
- 我搬得动  - 让我帮忙吧
- I got it.  - Let me help.
好了 放下来 好的
All right, set it down. All right.
等等!
Wait!
跑!
Run!
爸 快! 快!
Dad, come on! Come on!
爸 我们怎么办?
Dad, what do we do?
我应该可以用车挡住围栏
Maybe I could back the bus up against the fence.
挡得住吗?
Will it hold?
来
Come on.
放到口袋
Pockets.
拿着
Here.
- 好了吗?  - 好了
- Got it?  - Yep.
- 好 听着  - 好
- All right, listen to me.  - All right.
弹匣放进这里 这是枪栓
Magazine goes in here. Release is here.
记得上锁
Make sure it latches.
把操作杆往后拉
Pull back the operating rod
子弹就会到位
and rounds feed up.
一直扣动扳机才能速射 明白吗?
Keep squeezing the trigger for rapid fire, okay?
- 明白  - 开不了枪就赶紧跑
- All right.  - You shoot or you run.
别让他们靠近 知道吗?
Don't let 'em get close, okay?
后退!
Back off!
坚持住 Glenn
Hold on, Glenn.
我们还有东西的
We have something.
还有呢
We still have it.
婊子养的!
Son of a bitch.
爸爸
Daddy!
别射! 你会射穿那个袋的 要留给Glenn用
No! You could hit the bag. We need it for Glenn.
- 他在哪?  - 他在上面 100号房
- Where is he?  - He's up here. Cell 100.
他快窒息了!
He's turning blue!
保持他的呼吸道通畅 我来了
Clear his airway. I'm on the way.
- 爸  - 把他翻正
- Dad.  - Roll him on his back.
- 爸
- Dad.
往下拉他的肩膀
Hold his arms down.
撑住 小伙子
Come on, son.
撑住 你知道这样会没事的
Come on. You know how this works.
放松
Just relax.
坚持下去
Stay with us.
坚持下去...
Stay with us...
坚持下去
Stay with us.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
我们都会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
我不想让你来这
I didn't want you in here.
我知道
I know.
但是我必须在
I had to.
像你一样
Just like you.
爸爸
Daddy.
我叫你待在原地
I told you to stay put.
结束了吗?
Is it over?
希望如此 宝贝
I hope so, honey.
爸爸...
Dad...
一起都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be okay.
- Sasha呢? Sasha怎么样?  - 我不知道 抱歉
- Sasha? How's Sasha?  - I don't know. I'm sorry.
- 进去吧  - 我们带上这个
- Well, get in there.  - We got this.
爸爸...?
Dad...?
他们回来了 歇下吧
They're back now. Go rest.
# 你走吧 #
# Go your way #
# 我要绕远路 #
# I'll take the long way around #
# 我会找到下去的路 #
# I'll find my own way down #
# 如同我该做的那样 #
# As I should #
# 遥望远方 #
# And hold your gaze #
# 点石成金之道也有弊端 #
# There's coke in the Midas Touch #
# 玩笑中 我们老去 #
# A joke in the way that we rust #
# 再呼吸一次 #
# And breathe again #
# 你觉得迷茫 #
# And you'll find loss #
# 担心结果 #
# And you'll fear what you found #
# 风雨来临 #
# When weather comes #
# 撕裂... #
# Tearing down... #
需要帮忙吗?
Need some help with that?
不用 忙自己的事吧
No. Do your thing.
喂
Hey.
你没叫醒我
You didn't wake me up.
我想让你多睡会儿
I thought I'd let you sleep in.
- 我应该帮点忙  - 好
- I should help.  - Good.
我要找Daryl谈谈
I've got to go talk to Daryl.
现在吗?
Right now?
不是
No.
稍后 稍后
Soon. Soon.
- Glenn怎么样了?  - 他昨晚熬过来了
- How's Glenn doing?  - He made it through the night.
现在可以自己呼吸了
He's breathing on his own now.
Maggie和Bob正陪着他
Maggie and Bob are with him.
他情况稳定了 我可以松口气
He seems stable enough for me to get some air.
- 他真他妈的坚强  - 确实是
- He's a tough son of a bitch.  - He is.
你也是
You're a tough son of a bitch.
- 我确实是  - Carol呢?
- I am.  - How about Carol?
她和Lizzy在上面吗?
She up in a block with Lizzy?
不是 去跟Rick说说关于她的事吧
No. Talk to Rick about her.
她没事 跟Rick说吧
She's okay, just talk to him.
你要出去吗?
You heading out?
你要一起吗?
You want to come?
当然要
Hell, yeah.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 波特妹子 时间轴: 有个饭团
翻译: 初见 酱油影 Evayao
校对: 潇妹子